<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Python and R</title>
      <link>/blog/python-and-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/python-and-r/</guid>
      <description>R-Studio and Python are both fantastic coding programs that have the ability to work in tandem to share objects that can be used for manipulation in one language and visualization in the other, or vice versa.
As seen in this example,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Horse Colic</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>Colic is a cause for many horse emergencies in veterinary medicine due to the severity of the abdominal obstructions that may occur. Colic itself is not a diagnosis, but rather a symptom of a larger problem that is usually found in the Gastrointestinal tract. This dataset, found on Kaggle, consists of different parameters measuring the health of 209 horses with colic. The main variables I will be focusing on are surgery (yes or no), outcome (lived or died), abdomen, total protein, and packed cell volume.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have recently completed:
  Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools
  Modeling, Testing, and Classification
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sars vs. COVID-19</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>Virology has always excited me, and with the coronavirus looming around everywhere we go, I found it compelling to compare the current data regarding the deaths and confirmed cases of COVID-19 with it’s sister virus, SARS-CoV from 2003. Considering they are of the same genus and species of virus, I was expecting to find similar results regarding the number of deaths and rate of infection. As you will see, that is not at all the case.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>